# Cameron R. Lester

Phone: 818-584-4822 | Email: crl236@cornell.edu | LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/cameron-lester

# **MPS Graduate in Applied Statistics**

Data Scientist | Statistician | Community Leader

MPS graduate with 3+ years of experience in project work and client-facing data analyst roles. Passion for solving complex analytical problems to guide understanding and creative development decisions. Seeking to turn my love for data science into actionable insights to better our world.

#### **Education**

## **Cornell University**

Aug. 2019 – May 2020

Master of Professional Studies in Applied Statistics Emphasis in Data Science

- <u>Cumulative GPA:</u> 3.6/4.0
- Relevant Courses: Database Management and High-Performance Computing, Machine Learning for Data Science, Big Data Management and Analysis, Applied Statistical Computing with SAS
- <u>Certifications:</u> SAS Certified Base Programmer

### San Diego State University

Aug. 2016 – May 2019

Bachelor of Science in Statistics Emphasis in Computational Statistics

### **Experience**

### **Graduate Student Researcher**

Jan. 2020 - June 2020

Weill Cornell Medicine, Ithaca, NY

- **Experimental Design:** Utilized fMRI data of participants to produce four unique machine learning models that predicted average brain activation patterns based on presented visual stimuli.
- **Software Development**: Worked in Python using multiple computing libraries including Tensorflow, Scikit-learn, NumPy, Pandas, and Keras for building CNN, LSTM, and regularization models.
- **Project Management:** Organized my team's software development using agile methodology, presented findings and model performance to doctors on a weekly basis.

#### Office and Media Lead

Jan. 2016 – May 2019

San Diego State University Pride Center, San Diego, CA

- **Data Analysis:** Managed ETL of data on event attendance and resource usage, created key performance indicators to track campus event success leading to student retention rates of nearly 70% across events.
- **Front-End Web Development:** Curated web pages using Toolbox and HTML with a focus on connecting students to both campus and local resources, increasing traffic by an average annual rate of over 25%.
- **Data Visualization:** Designed infographics to translate LGBTQ+ student needs and experiences as part of a semester-long educational workshop attended by over 30 healthcare professionals and administrators.

#### **Technical Skills**

- Relational Databases: SQL (MySQL, HiveQL)
- **Big Data**: Hadoop, Pig, Hive, Spark, Ambari
- **Software:** R, SAS, Python, Java, C#
- ML Models: Random Forest, SVM, NLP, GAN
- Cloud Infrastructure: Cloudera, AWS
- Microsoft Office: Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook
- Quantitative Analysis: Time Series, Forecasting
- **Data Processing**: Map Reduce, Elastic Search